### < Nicolas Mewhirter />

Email: <a href="mailto:mewhirter@wisc.edu">mewhirter@wisc.edu</a> | Phone: 608-642-1693 | Website: <a href="https://nicolasm42.github.io/">https://nicolasm42.github.io/</a>

### Personal Summary------

Ambitious, creative programmer with a desire to make my mark on the world of software development. From my time at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, as-well as through interning and working on personal projects, I've gained the experience and skills necessary to be successful in my ever-expanding field.

# Work Experience-----

#### **Software Developer Intern**

Epic | Verona, WI | Full-time | June 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Worked as a developer on an internal software project
- Attended team meetings, collected feedback on my work from fellow developers and UX designers
- Presented my work to interested external parties, demoed to other full-time developers

#### **Student Assistant (Level 3)**

University of Wisconsin-Madison, College Library Computer Lab | Part-time | Sept. 2019 - May 2021

- Fulfilled patron inquiries and requests
- Troubleshooted patron's technology related issues
- Maintained an approachable and helpful attitude

### Education-----

#### **University of Wisconsin-Madison**

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science | Certificate, Mathematics | 3.813/4.000 | 2017-2021

Awards and Activities:

- Graduated with Distinguished Honors: ranked within the top 20% of the College of Letters & Science
- Dean's List: Fall 2017, Spr/Fall 2018, Spr/Fall 2019
- Intramural Soccer: Team Manager and Player (Fall 2017 Spring 2020)
- Intramural Dodgeball: Team Manager and Player (Fall 2017 Spring 2020)
- Intramural Rocket League: Player (Fall 2019 Spring 2021)

## Projects------

**Badger Textbooks:** Team-based senior project. Developed a React web-app designed to be the 'goto' application for UW-Madison students looking to sell their used textbooks to other UW students. Worked as a part of a six student team to complete the application while following a modified waterfall SD lifecycle.

- Technologies Used: VSCode, JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Firebase, Github

**Final Defender: The Last Stand:** Personal project. Developed a game that is currently available on the Apple App Store. Worked to design and develop an 'arcade-style' game and actively monitor the game's status and provide updates as needed.

- Technologies Used: XCode, Swift, Photoshop

**Personal Website:** Personal project. Developed a website to serve as a 'one-stop-shop' to advertise information about me, my resume, and projects I've worked on.

- Technologies Used: VSCode, HTML, Bootstrap, hosted with Github Pages

### Skills-----

**Technical:** Java, JavaScript, Python, Swift, C++, C, SQL, CSS, React, Agile Methodologies, Object Oriented

Programming, Mathematics, Photoshop

Interpersonal: Team Leadership, Communication, Teamwork